Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union PE.003
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Printed Ephemera Collection on the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union
1909-1990
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library
PE.003
2 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
The Printed Ephemera Collection on the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union is an artificial collection, collected and assembled by the Tamiment Library over the course of several decades. Material in the collection originates with the national bodies of the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union as well as the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union and the Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America. The collection also contains material from locals around the country, most notably, from Bakers' Union Local 3 of New York City, which was formed as a Local for all New York City bakers who were previously organized as small, often ethnically based locals.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into two series. Folders are arranged alphabetically within series. Series I: General Files, 1909-1990; Series II: Locals, 1924-1989.
The collection is arranged into two series. Folders are arranged alphabetically within series.
Missing Title
Series I: General Files, 1909-1990
Series II: Locals, 1924-1989
Custodial History
The provenance of the materials is varied. Items were obtained through purchases, donations, standing orders with publishers, arrangements with labor unions and other organizations, exchanges with other libraries, and through ongoing collecting by Tamiment staff.
Historical/Biographical Note
The Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America, a pioneer of the North American labor movement, was organized in 1886. In 1969, it united with the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union. Again, in 1978, the Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America saw that it had common goals with the Tobacco Workers International Union, and so the two merged, creating the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. As another merger occurred in 1999 with the American Federation of Grain Millers, the union is known today as the Bakery, Confectionery, Tobacco Workers, and Grain Millers International Union. As of 2009, the Union represented more than 120,000 workers in both Canada and the United States and its dedication remains strong in bringing economic and social justice to all workers in its jurisdiction.
Scope and Content Note
The material in the Printed Ephemera Collection on the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union ranges in date from 1909-1990 and was generated by the international and national bodies of the Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union as well as the Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of American and the American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union. The collection consists of agreements, contracts, constitutions, by-laws, and reports, as well as printed ephemera such as fliers, brochures, newspaper clippings, pamphlets and other publications. Locals from around the country also have material in the collection. Notably, Bakers Union Local 3 of New York City consists of constitutions, pamphlets and publications as well as fliers, materials from rank and file committees, and documents related to various strikes of local New York businesses.
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Bakery, Confectionary and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 3 Records (WAG 135)
Bakery, Confectionary and Tobacco Workers International Union, Local 3 Photographs (PHOTOS 108)
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Materials in this collection have been compiled by the Tamiment Library.
Constitutions.; Broadsides (notices); Articles.; Agreements.; Publications (documents); Pamphlets.; Bakery employees |x Labor unions.; Minutes (administrative records); Labor unions; Labor unions -- United States.; Fliers (printed matter); Reports.; Circular letters.; Clippings (information artifacts); Proceedings.; Bylaws (administrative records).; Bakery and Confectionery Workers International Union of America; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union. Local 3 (Long Island City, N.Y.); American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union; Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union
- Series I: General Files, 1909-1990
  - American Bakery and Confectionary Workers' International Union: Constitutions, 1958-1966 (Box 1)
  - American Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union: Newspaper Clippings and Articles on, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: Agreements and Contracts, 1980-1981 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: Constitutions, 1978-1990 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: General Executive Board, 1980 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: General Executive Board, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: General Executive Board, 1982 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: Pamphlets and Publications, 1982-1990, undated (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: Pennsylvania State Board, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bakery, Confectionery, and Tobacco Workers International Union: Pension Plan, Increases in: Correspondence Regarding, 1981 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Book of Constitution and Laws (in English and Various Languages), 1918 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Constitutions, 1909-1962 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Constitutions, 1965-1974 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Fliers, undated (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board, 1937, 1957, 1963 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board, Mar 1972 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board, Sep 1972 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board, 1975 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board: Minutes, Feb 1962 - Dec 1965 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: General Executive Board: Minutes, Mar 1966 - Jan 1969 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Joint Executive Board of Greater New York, 1945 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Local Union Roster, 1962 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Newspaper Clippings and Articles on, 1940 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Pamphlets and Publications, 1939, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Bakery and Confectionery Workers' International Union of America: Pension Fund, 1959, 1970-1979, undated (Box 1)
- Series II: Locals, 1924-1989
  - Local 1 (New York, NY), 1943, undated (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Agreements and Contracts, 1956 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Agreements and Contracts, 1959 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Agreements and Contracts, 1960-1966 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Agreements and Contracts, 1970-1974 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Agreements and Contracts, 1975-1989 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Annual Cake Show and Trade Exhibit, 1960-1961 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Bickford's Strike, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): By-laws and Charter Presentation, 1955-1976 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Circular Letters, 1961, 1963, undated (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Fliers and Ephemera, 1959-1976 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): New Leadership Committee, 1970 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Pamphlets and Publications, 1963 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Pension/Welfare Fund, 1965-1977 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Standard Contracts, 1962-1968 (Box 2)
  - Local 3 (New York, NY): Standard Contracts, 1971-1987 (Box 2)
  - Local 6 (Philadelphia, PA), 1946 (Box 2)
  - Local 50 (Candy and Confectionery Union, Long Island City, NY), 1960 (Box 2)
  - Local 50 (Candy and Confectionery Union, Long Island City, NY): Placard, 1992-1993 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 4)
  - Local 51 (Cake Bakers' Union, New York, NY), 1940, 1947, 1959, undated (Box 2)
  - Local 118 (Washington, DC), 1977 (Box 2)
  - Local 181 (Toronto Bakers' Union, Toronto, Canada), 1937 (Box 2)
  - Local 269 (Matzo and Noodle Workers Union, New York, NY), 1967 (Box 2)
  - Local 348 (Cambridge, MA), 1940 (Box 2)
  - Local 358 (Richmond, VA), undated (Box 2)
  - Local 405 (New York, NY), undated (Box 2)
  - Local 464 (Hershey, PA), 1924-1935 (Box 2)
  - Local 484 (Long Island City, NY), 1962 (Box 2)
  - Local 505 (NY), 1931-1939 (Box 2)